

jtluns9@yahoo.com | 925-673-1600 | Napa, CA 94558

Summary

Jacob is known by his friends and colleagues as a competitor. Whether it's sports or working for the family business, he strives to work hard and be a better version of himself every day. Doing things right plays a fundamental role for Jacob in and out of the workplace and no achievement matters more than holding himself to high standards of integrity. After working several years in sales Jacob decided to switch things up and began learning about Cybersecurity through the University of California Berkeley. He was instantly hooked and obtained a professional certificate in Information and Cybersecurity as well as the CompTIA Security+ certification. He's looking forward to making a difference stopping bad guys and protecting the world's information.

Skills

- Firewall and Endpoint Hardening
- Governance, Risk, and Compliance (GRC)
- Security Information and Event Management
- Network Security, TCP/IP Protocols

- IT Systems Engineering
- Ethical Hacking/Penetration Testing
- Programming Languages: JavaScript, Python, CSS/HTML, Django, SQL
- Source and Version Control: Git, Github

Experience

HomePro Solutions | Napa, CA **Cyber Security Analyst** 02/2024 - Current

- Monitoring intrusion detection systems, firewalls, and antivirus software to identify any potential threats
- Assessing the organization's systems and networks for vulnerabilities by conducting scans and audits
- Maintaining detailed records of security incidents, investigations, and remediation efforts

Holsby Bears Basketball | Sweden Semi-Pro Basketball Player 10/2018 - 04/2019

- Motivated and encouraged teammates as the captain of the team
- Leading scorer and rebounder averaging 20+ points per game
- Led the team to their best record in over a decade

Education and Training

University of California Berkeley | Berkeley, CA | 2023 **Professional Certificate**, Information and Cybersecurity

- Finished in top 4% of the class
- CompTia Security+ Certified

University of Denver | Denver, CO | 2015-2018

Bachelor of Arts in Business Administration

- Dean's List every year
- Guard for DU Men's Basketball

Websites, Portfolios, Profiles

- Jalu589.pythonanywhere.com
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/jacob-lunsford9
- https://github.com/jalu589